Margherita Toussaint

ms.r.toussaint@gmail.com https://rita-toussaint.net

About

Enjoys coding, creating and researching and wants to improve the world. Experience in bug tracking, project management, incident response, app publishing and Agile, well-versed in React, Bootstrap, Tailwind and Javascript, currently learning Angular.

Skills and Achievements

Stack - HTML, CSS, Python 3, Javascript, React, Next, Flask, Java, SQL, Spring, Bootstrap, Tailwind, MongoDB

O'Reilly Scholarship Recipient

- Fluent in French
- AWS Cerified Cloud Practitioner
- CACHE Level 3 Certificate in Understanding Mental Health

Recent History

Intrepid English: WordPress Developer, App Tester and Incident Responder (March 2023 - present)

- learned how to use Wordpress
- learned how to effectively test websites and apps and how to keep a thorough record of bugs
- published and maintained apps on Google Play and Apple App Store
- responded to website and app bugs immediately

CodeClan: Software Development Bootcamp (November 2022 - March 2023)

- learned how to write full-stack programs and websites in 16 weeks
- learned how to code according to TDD best practices
- designed and built 3 projects in Python, React and Java
- learned about version control and how to use Git

Pega Architect: With You With Me (March 2022 - October 2022)

- became a qualified Pega Systems and Business Architect and acquired Cloud Practitioner certification for AWS
- managed a project which was then presented to the company and CEO
- was part of the company's Neurodiversity Steering Group and gave presentations on how to be a good ally to neurodiverse people
- trained in Agile and Scrum and gave new hires a lecture on User Stories

Projects

<u>Disney+ Clone</u> - a website based on streaming service, Disney+ (personal project, 2023)

Here, I learned how to use Tailwind, Next.js and Vite. I used The Movie Database's (TMDB) API to populate arrays of films and TV shows which could be clicked through and clicked on to view more information on each film or programme.

<u>furFinder</u> - a Tinder-like app where the user can adopt a pet from a shelter and where admin can access adoption requests (group project, 2023)

This was my first group project and we were instructed to build a CRUD app in React using APIs. My team and I decided to build a Tinder-like app where users could apply to adopt a cat or a dog from a shelter and the shelter could see and archive those applications as well as add, update or delete animals depending on their adoption status. We

created our own database of animals in MongoDB. This took 6 days to complete, and we had to follow it up with a presentation.

<u>ArrrrPG</u> - a nostalgic text-based roleplaying game about pirates (solo capstone project, 2023)

This was my final project where I wrote the backend in Java Spring and the frontend in React. I wrote the characters and story, designed the battles and had to carefully plan the game logic. This took 13 days to complete and I had to follow it up with a presentation.

NoteClan - a studio booking service (solo project, 2022)

This was my first project at CodeClan. We were instructed to build a simple CRUD app using Python and Flask and I chose to build a studio booking service based on my own experiences in booking studios. The user could add, edit or delete bookings for three studios. This took 4 days to complete. After completion, I had to give a presentation on my project.

Employment History

Lead Volunteer: Oxfam Bookshops (March 2020 - February 2022)

- operated the tills, recorded profits and instructed new volunteers on how to do the same
- sorted donated items according to genre and priced them based on condition
- uploaded items to the Oxfam Shop website

Volunteer: Glasgow International Festival (July 2021)

 greeted visitors at the exhibition, provided information about it and directed them to Track and Trace

Volunteer: Glasgow Pride (July 2018)

- signed in all volunteers upon their arrival to the site
- assisted with the Disability/Children's Booth

Volunteer: RCTV Memoria & Xchange Scotland (August 2011 - July 2012)

- corrected and wrote English documents
- researched and raised awareness of the problem of torture and its survivors

Education

At Glasgow Clyde College:

NPA and PDA Cyber Security (2021)
 Learned the basics of cyber hygiene and cyber security, including social engineering, networks and simple penetration testing.

At the University of Glasgow:

- **MLitt Comparative Literature (2019)**In doing this course, I learned about the

challenges that go into translation in marketing as well as localisation in video games. I also successfully gave presentations and led two seminars, which improved my skills in public speaking and project management.

- MA French – 2:1 (2017)

Achieved French fluency and learn

Achieved French fluency and learned how to conduct research effectively.